Hello Namaskar Jai Hind Vande Mataram.  You are watching
Jio News and we have brought for you
quick big news of selected importance from the country, world and your state and city.  But
before that, if you have not subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe to the channel and turn on the bell notification
and like and
share this video as much as possible.  Today's question for you before looking at the big news.
Which is the coldest planet in the solar system?  Option A Mercury, Option B
Uranus, Option C Neptune
, Option D Saturn.  Answer this question by
commenting and tell us which state and city's
news do you want to see more?
Tell us by commenting so that we
can show more news of your state or city.  Let us now see
today's quick big news.
West Bengal CM Shubhendu said
Bangladeshis should run away from here quickly.
Infiltrators will not be sent to jail.  He is not the son-in-law
who will make you sit and feed you.
Bangladeshis started gathering at the border.  West Bengal
CM Suvendu Adhikari
asked Bangladeshis to leave the country.  He said that
Bangladeshis living illegally in the state should be identified and
handed over to the police.  After which BSF
will help in their return.  He said
run away from here quickly otherwise action will be taken.  We will
not feed the infiltrators by sending them to jail.
He is not the son-in-law, he will be chased away.
Their Bangladesh officials have also
said that they will take our people.
Here in North 24 Parganas of West Bengal,
more than 100 foreign nationals have gathered at Hakimpur check post since Tuesday morning.  It
is claimed that these people were
living illegally in different parts of West Bengal and are now
reaching the border to return to Bangladesh.
Mohan government is again taking a
loan of ₹2800 crore.  Auction of securities through RBI's eCer platform.  The
debt in the current financial year was ₹9200 crore.
Mohan Yadav's government of Madhya Pradesh is going to
take a big loan once again in the last week of May.   The
state government is raising a
loan of ₹2800 crore through the Reserve Bank of India in two separate
tranches of ₹1600
crore and ₹1200 crore.
This is the fourth time in the current financial year 2026
that the government is borrowing from the market and
with this, the total borrowing done so far in this financial year has
reached ₹9200 crore.
According to the notification issued by the Finance Department, the state government is taking this loan by
issuing bonds through RBI under Madhya Pradesh State Development Loan.  The first
amount will be ₹1600 crore on which
interest has been fixed at 7.64%.  The second amount will be
₹10 crore on which 7.83%
interest will have to be paid.  The government will repay both loans
in six monthly installments in April and
October.
Amit Shah said that anti-drone systems will be installed on the border.  The
Pakistanis had to turn their backs and run away from Sanchu post in Rajasthan.
Had breakfast at the border.  Union
Home Minister Amit Shah visited the
Sanchu post of Border Security Force (BSF) in Bikaner.
During this, he said in the police conference
that I have come to the historical post Sanchu.
I had a desire to visit Sanchu Chowki
even before becoming the Home Minister and
during the 1964 India-Pakistan war, the population of Sanchu was
more than 500.  The RAC post was
500 meters behind in Ranjitpura village.   It was
reported that Pakistan had launched an offensive to capture Sanchu.
Then, three
RAC and 13 Grenadier soldiers
attacked here and kept Sanchu within the Indian border.  The
soldiers fulfilled this responsibility
and the Pakistanis had to turn their backs and run away from here.
Claim: 19 lakh trucks stopped due to diesel price hike,
freight charges increased by 15%.  Food
items may become expensive.  Due to the increase in the price of diesel,
transporters have started parking their trucks.  The
situation is such that out
of the 95 lakh trucks present across the country,
about 20% i.e. 19 lakh trucks have been removed from the roads.
This claim has been made in the report of Economic Times.
According to reports,
due to shortage of diesel and high prices,
transport companies have also increased freight charges.
Fares on key routes like West to North India have increased by 10 to 15%.
30 km  Even the prices of local transportation have
increased even more.  This will have a direct
impact on the pockets of the common people because the
prices of fruits, vegetables and ration may increase in the coming days.
Taiwan overtook the Indian stock market.
Market cap in AI and chip sector rapidly crosses Rs 415 lakh crore.  India's
value is ₹413 lakh crore.  Let us tell you that Taiwan has
left India behind in terms of stock market value i.e. market cap.
In the era of Artificial Intelligence (AI), the
huge rise in the shares of Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Company, the world's largest chip maker, has
given Taiwan this lead.  According to Bloomberg,
Taiwan's market cap
reached 4.95 trillion, or about 415 lakh crore, by Monday.
Whereas India's value fell to 4.92
trillion i.e. around 413 lakh crores.
This makes Taiwan one of the top five stock markets in the world,
after the US, China, Japan and Hong Kong.
Fraud case against Anil Ambani Group companies.  Took a loan of Rs 150 crore with fake documents.
Then
sent the money to other companies.  A
case of fraud and criminal conspiracy has been
registered against the then directors of companies associated with the Anil Ambani Group.  The Economic
Officers Wing of Mumbai Police has registered this case at the Cuffe Parade Police
Station.  The accused are
accused of taking a loan of ₹150 crore from the bank, transferring it to other purposes and defaulting.  According to EOW sources,
the action was taken on the complaint of Axis Bank Vice
President Prakash Prabhakar Rao
and the bank said that the
accused had conspired with the intention of causing financial loss and fraud to the bank.
This is the second FIR registered on the complaint of Axis Bank against companies linked to Anil Dhirubhai Ambani Group (ADAG).
Silver fell by ₹4,750 to ₹2,66,000.  It has
fallen below ₹1,20,000 from its all-time high.
Gold became cheaper by ₹1,135.  There has been a decline in the prices of gold and silver
and according to the India
Bullion and Jewellers Association (IBJA), the
price of 1 kg silver has decreased by ₹4,750 to
₹2,66,000.  The price of 10 grams of 24
carat gold has fallen by ₹1,135 to
₹1,58,000.
ClaimIran shot down US MQ9 Reaper drone.
US attacks Iranian boats near Hormuz
, missile site also
targeted.  Iran claimed to have
shot down a US MQ9B drone
and also fired on a fighter jet that entered Iranian airspace.
According to Al Jazeera report, Iran's Islamic
Revolutionary Guard Corps (
IRGC) has said that Iranian forces have taken action against an
RQ4 drone and an intruding F35
fighter plane.  The IRGC has
warned that Iran has the right to retaliate if the US
violates the ceasefire.
Meanwhile, Iran
's supreme leader Mustaba Khamenei has also
issued a statement.  He has said that
the powers of West Asia will
no longer provide a shield for American military bases and
America will no longer have any safe haven in this region.
Australia
raised the issue of Hormuz in the Delhi Quad meeting.  Said
freedom of sea routes is necessary.  Jaishankar said
consensus was reached on three major decisions.  The meeting of
foreign ministers of Quad countries has ended in the country's capital Delhi
and in this
Australia raised the issue of Fermooz.
Foreign Minister Penny Wong said that the impact of Iran's
closure of Faramuz province is
now visible on oil and energy supplies.   The
Quad countries say that it is important that the sea routes
remain open and there should not be
any toll or restrictions on the ships passing through there.
Pakistan said it will not accept Israel as a country.
Compromise on ideology is not acceptable.
Trump had asked Muslim countries to
befriend Israel.  Pakistan has refused to
befriend Israel and recognize it as a country.
Pakistan's Defence
Minister Khawaja Asif said that Pakistan
cannot compromise on its fundamental ideologies.
Asif said that how can we sit with those people
whose words
cannot be trusted even for a day.
Pakistan is probably the only country in the world
whose passport states that it
is not valid for Israel and this makes Pakistan
's stand completely clear and there will be no
change in it.   A
Chunari made of 5100 sarees was offered to Mother Ganga.  Abhishek with 501 litres of milk.
Crowds at the ghats of Ayodhya on Ganga Dussehra.
Ganga Dussehra was celebrated in UP on Tuesday.
Crowds of devotees gathered at the ghats in many cities of Uttar Pradesh including Varanasi, Prayagraj, Ayodhya since morning.
5100 sarees and 25,500 feet long Chunari brought from 12 states were offered to Mother Ganga at 80 ghats of Kashi.
Ganga was anointed with 501 litres of milk.
Thousands of
devotees offered
prayers to the Sun after taking bath at Sangam in Prayagraj.  Devotees are also doing charity at Saryu Ghat in Ayodhya.
Devotees are reaching the ghats singing bhajans
and by 12:00 am in Kashi,
1.5 lakh devotees have taken a dip in the Ganga.
5 lakh people have taken bath in Sangam in Prayagraj.
In Ayodhya also,
more than 500 devotees have taken a dip in Saryu.   There will be an
investigation into places where there has been a sudden change in population.  The Central Government
formed a committee.  Home Minister Amit Shah said infiltration is a
big challenge for the country.  The Central Government has
constituted a high-level committee to study the abnormal changes taking place in the country's population
and Justice Prakash Prabhakar Naolekar Rita has been
made its chairperson.  Union
Home Minister Amit Shah said in this post
that this committee will assess the population changes taking place across India due to illegal infiltration and other unusual
reasons.  Along with this, it will also
study the patterns of abnormal changes at the level of religious and social communities and
provide solutions.  He wrote that
abnormal population change due to infiltration and other reasons is a
big challenge for the present and future of any nation
and to deal with this challenge,
Prime Minister Narendra Modi had
announced a high level committee on 15 August 2025.   The
Supreme Court
formed a monitoring committee for waste management.  Action will be taken against illegal dumping and transportation of garbage.
Collectors will give reports on the website of every district.   The
Supreme Court heard the case
after receiving reports from states on compliance with solid waste management rules.  The
court said that those involved in
illegal transportation and illegal dumping of waste should be
identified.  The District Collector has been
instructed to take strict action against such vehicles and their
owners or operators.   The
court said that a
separate page for solid waste management should be created on the website of every district
and the collector will upload the
current status of waste management, improvements being made and
photographs of old waste on this page and
submit a report.  The deadline for disposal of old waste accumulated over the years will
not be extended.
Ram Rahim came out of jail again.  She came out
of Rohtak jail on parole for the 16th time in 9 years with eight luxury
cars.  Reached Sirsa camp.
Dera Sacha Sauda chief Gurmeet Ram Rahim is
out of jail once again.  He left Rohtak's Sunaria jail on
May 26 at 6:30 am on a 30-day parole
and
reached Sirsa Dera at around 5:15 am.  His convoy
included eight expensive vehicles like Toyota Land Cruiser Fortuner LD.
This is the 16th parole for Ram Rahim, who is serving a life sentence for sexual assault on women, and the
second time he has come out of jail in the first five months of this year.
He was granted 40 days parole in January 2026 and
returned to jail in February.
After being sentenced in 2017, the Dera chief has
already been granted parole and furlough 16 times.
Delhi Gymkhana Club
asked the government for land at another place.  The Centre had asked for the return of 27.3 acres of land.
Order to vacate by June 5.  The General Committee formed by the Central Government for the 113-year-old
Delhi Gymkhana Club has
appealed to the government
not to affect the functioning of the club.  The committee
said that if the government proceeds with the possession action, the
club should be given land at another place.
Actually, the historic club located in Lutyens Delhi has a
ground rent due of about ₹48 crore.  The
Land and Development Office had
sent notices to the club management in September 2025, March 2026 and April 2026.   The
last notice issued in April
asked for the outstanding amount to be deposited within a week.  Along with this, a warning was given
that if the payment was not made, the club's 27.3 acres of
land would be taken back.  After this, on May 22, the
club was ordered to vacate the campus by June 5.
CNG ₹2 costlier in Delhi, price ₹83.9
per kg.  Prices increased for the fourth time this month.
So far, an increase of ₹6 has taken place.  Amid the Iran war, the
prices of compressed natural gas (CNG) have increased for the fourth time in the last two weeks.
Indraprastha Gas Limited (
IGL) on May 26 increased the price of CNG by ₹2 per
kg
in several cities, including Delhi NCR.
Six people lost their lives due to storm in Uttar Pradesh.
Banda's mercury crossed 47° Celsius for the eighth consecutive day.
Monsoon 35 km from Keralam
Stuck away.  Punjab, Haryana, Rajasthan in the north-west of the country,
Delhi,
Himachal, UP in the north, Odisha in the south-west and
Telangana are facing severe heat.   The
most dangerous phase of heat is going on in Gujarat, Maharashtra in the west and Madhya Pradesh, the part of Maharashtra adjoining MP and Chhattisgarh in Central India.
According to the Indian Meteorological Department,
Banda in Uttar Pradesh and Brahmapuri in Vidarbha were the
hottest.  Temperatures above 47°C were recorded here for the eighth day.
Khajuraho in Chhatarpur was at third place with 47.2°C
and Naugaon was the
fourth hottest city with 46.8°C.   There was a
storm and hurricane in Gonda, Lakhimpur, Kheri, Basti, Shahjahanpur and Sitapur of UP amid the heat.
Six people, including a child, lost their lives in accidents related to this.  Talking about
monsoon, it has been
30 to 35 km away from the coast of Keralam for the last 3 days.  It is stuck far away
and due to pre-monsoon, there is
rain in the coastal areas of Kerala, Tamil Nadu and Karnataka.
If you want to watch weather news
then its videos are also uploaded on our channel.
You can see them.  Today's
good luck: No problem is actually as
big as we
make it by thinking about it again and again.  Do let us know how you liked this video
in the comment section.  If you
liked the video then please like and share the video
and to watch such interesting videos
subscribe to our channel Jio News
and press the bell icon and do check
our playlist and community tab to watch our old and latest videos.
So see you in the next video.
Thank you for now.